#哈喽大家好
Hi everyone
#我们上次杀的猪
The pig that we butchered last time...
#我留了一块五花肉起来
I kept a block of pork belly
```I kept a piece of pork belly
#跟大家分享做红烧肉
to share with you how to cook "Hong Shao Rou" (Braised pork)
#这次做红烧肉我就不用酱油
This time I will not use soybean sauce
```This time I will not use soy sauce
#用一种老方法来做看一下味道怎么样
Instead, I will try an old-fashioned way of cooking and see how it tastes
#这个猪肉的话我们是冻过的
We have frozen the meat in advance
#为什么要冻一下呢
Why freeze it?
#冻了之后切起来更好看一些
Because frozen meat looks better after cutting
#漆二娃
Qi Er Wa
#诶
Yes
#你去扯点小葱嘛
Can you pick some green onions?
#我把这个肉洗哈
I'm gonna wash the meat
#我们这个肉最好是冻一下
It's better to freeze the meat first
#冻一下之后再拿来烧
After freezing, burn it with flame
#烧完之后再切
And cut it into slices at last
```Then, cut it into slices
#为了就是要这个五花肉工工整整的
That's how to make the pork slices uniform
```So that the pork slices have uniform shape
#你看把这个黑的洗完了之后
Look, after you remove the burnt, black layer
#这个不会有发苦的味道
The meat will not taste bitter
#摘四五颗就够了
Four or five should be enough
#好
Ok
#再清洗一次
Wash it again
#这个菜还特别适合老人孩子吃
This dish is really suitable for old people and children
#因为牙口不好的红烧肉烧软一点
Because the meat can be boiled till very soft such that they can enjoy even if their teeth are not strong
#好
Ok
#切一下
Let's cut it
#你看嘛
Look
#我们这个肉的话
The meat...
#冻一下再切红烧肉切的刀口非常的工整
The meat can be cut into nice and uniform pieces if it's frozen in advance
#我们现在先切成条等一下再切成块
Let's cut it into strips and then into cubes
#切成麻将那么大要的不
What about mahjong-size?
#可以
Ok
#切这么大要得不
How about this size?
#要得
Okay
#反正烧它得软为原则嘛
Anyway, as long as it can be cooked thoroughly
#像这么大一坨的你能吃几坨四伯爷
How many pieces like this can you eat, uncle?
#10多坨都不吃啊
More than 10 pieces
#10坨啊
10 pieces?
#10坨以上嘛
More than 10 pieces
#你年轻的时候呢？
What about when you were young?
#年轻的时候还没得这个时候厉害
I couldn't eat as much as I do now
#还没这个时候吃得
Not this much?
#这个时候还干得点
Now I can eat a lot
#年轻的时候是没得都嘛
When you were young, there was not so much meat actually
#嗯
That's true
#你猜这一盆肉有多重
Guess how heavy this bowl of meat is
#6，7斤嘛
About 6 or 7 Jin (3 - 3.5 kg)
#拿给你猜到了6斤半
You got it. It's 6.5 Jin
#好 现在差不多了
Ok. Now this's almost done
#准备点配料
Let's prepare some side ingredients
#这个红烧肉不用放什么东西就是姜葱加冰糖
To cook the "Hong shao rou", you need to add nothing but green onion, ginger, and crystal sugar
#再加2斤白酒
And 2 Jin of white wine
#放点香料就可以了
and some spices
#不用放酱油
No need for soybean sauce
#这个葱把它挽成节
Knot the green onions
#等一下烧肉的时候放进去烧
I'll put it into the pot while cooking the meat
#然后再敲一点冰糖
Then crush some crystal sugar
#这个冰糖主要是炒糖色用的
to make the caramel
#这里6斤肉配3颗八角够了
We have 6 Jin of meat. 3 star anises would be enough
#然后再配一块桂皮增加这个肉香味
Along with a piece of cassia bark to enhance the flavor of the pork
#好了 开始做吧
Ok. Let's start cooking!
#漆二娃 火烧大点哦
Qi Er Wa, please make the fire stronger
#好的
Ok~
#我先把这个肉焯下水
I'm gonna boil the meat first
#这个肉冷水下锅焯水
Start boiling the meat when the water is still cold
#烧燃没有哦
Have you lit it up?
#好像不是很燃
Not really
#烧不燃我来
Let me try if you can't light it
#好 你来四伯爷
Okay. Please, uncle
#好嘛
Ok
#你来
Come on
#火都烧不燃还说自己是农村人
How can you claim that you come from the countryside but are unable to light the fire?
#好 让开嘛让开让开
Okay okay. Just step aside
#让让让 我来我来
Step aside and let me do this
#你看我们走起来两下就把它烧燃
See? We can light it up in a few seconds
#这个酒有点霸道
The wine is kind of strong
#喝得到几口嘛
How much can you drink?
#喝不得 我喝不得酒
No... I can't drink much
#嘿嘿 喝不得
Haha. Can't drink?
#等会儿这个肉全部是放酒来烧的哦
The meat will be boiled with wine later
#不关事
Doesn't matter
#干醉了好打醉拳
I can play drunken boxing when I get drunk
#不得不得
You won't get drunk
#这个烧了之后没得酒味道得
The dish will not taste like wine after boiling
#没得酒精的
There's no alcohol left
#因为它都挥发了
The alcohol is gone during boiling
#刚哥 你这个水是要把它烧好久哦
Do you want to boil it with the water here for a long time?
#还是要把这个肉煮好了就起锅了
Or will you take out the meat when it's done?
#这个焯到它浮沫出来完
I need to boil it till all the scum is spat out
#就是没得浮沫为止
Until no more scum goes out?
#嗯
Yes
#好现在要准备把这个肉捞出来了
Ok. Now I need to take out the meat
#现在准备放一点油
Now add some oil into the wok
#然后再把这个肉倒进去爆炒一会儿
and stir-fry the meat for a while
#刚开始这个油要少放一点
In the beginning, you should not pour much oil into the wok
#只要能润到锅就行了
As long as it's enough to grease the wok
#好 少放一点油
Okay. A little oil is enough
#然后把这个肉倒进去爆一下
Then fry the meat for a while
#哦 变颜色了
Oh. The color is changing
#现在大家可以看到这里面已经开始冒油了
Now you can see that the fat is coming out of the meat
#如果怕油腻的话就多炒一会儿把这个油爆干一点
If you don't like greasy food, cook it for a longer time to remove more fat
#爆干了有什么吃头没得油气的
It won't taste good if it's too dry
#没有那么腻 香点
It will be less greasy and will smell better
#不好吃
Nah... Not delicious
#把这个肉捞起来
Take out the meat
#好啦 现在要准备炒糖色了
Ok. Now we need to cook the caramel
#加一点点水
Add a little water
#这个加一点点水进去
Add a little water into the wok
#因为这个火候不怎么好控制所以就用水来炒
It's hard to control the heat here, so I use some water to cook the caramel
#把火烧起嘛
Light the fire
#其实炒这个糖色非常的简单
It's actually very easy to cook the caramel
#就是炒到它从酱油色变成深褐色
When it turns from soy-sauce-color into deep brown
#然后就加开水下去就可以了
Add some boiled water into the wok
#四伯爷闻到焦糖味没
Uncle, can you smell the caramel?
#闻到了
Yeah
#还差一点
Not ready yet
#现在是在冒大泡
Now big bubbles are coming out
#要等到它大泡冒完重新起来小泡的时候就加水
We should add water when big bubbles disappear and small bubbles come out again
#要开始要变小泡了
Now small bubbles appear
#好开始变成红色了
Ok. It's turning red
#好现在小泡起来啦
Now the small bubbles are coming out
#看准时机
This is the right time
#好 加水
Ok! Add water now
#这个水加得刚刚好
The water is added at the perfect time
#看到没这个糖色
See? The caramel
#我尝一下就知道了
I'll know if it's good by simply tasting it
#没有味道
It's got no flavor
#没有味道的糖色是刚刚好的
The caramel with no flavor is just perfect
#好啦 现在我们把肉放下去
Okay. Let's put the meat inside
#把它翻炒一下
Stir-fry it a little bit
#好 均匀的时候放这个香料
Ok. When it's mixed up, put the spices into the wok
#放这个姜葱
and green onion and ginger
#好差不多了
Ok. Almost there
#然后再放这个白酒
Pour the wine into the wok
#我这里准备的是2斤白酒
Here I've got 2 Jin of white wine
#2斤白酒应该是不够的
2 Jin may not be enough
#为了节省一点
To save the wine
#加点水
add some water instead
#刚好没过红烧肉就可以了
The liquid should just submerge the meat
#没过这个肉
submerge the meat
#然后盖上锅盖
Then cover the wok
#盖上锅盖把它烧开
Cover the wok and boil the water
#烧开了之后再调一点味道
When boiling, add some seasonings
#好啦 现在开了
Ok. It's boiling now
#这个开了之后就开始调味
As I said, add the seasonings after boiling
#其实这个菜是不应该加水的
Actually, water shouldn't have been added into this dish
#因为白酒没有够为了节省一点
It's just because I don't have enough white wine...
#自己家里面吃就随便一点就好了
We don't have to be so serious since this is a home-made dish
#我刚刚放了一块冰糖现在再放点盐
I just put a piece of crystal sugar. Now I'm gonna add some salt
#这个盐的量一定要掌握好
You must be precise about the amount of salt
#不能太咸也不能淡
It should neither be too salty nor too light
#好 刚刚好
Ok. That's the right amount
#然后开了的时候这个浮沫也要去一下
When it's boiling, the scum should also be removed
#这个浮沫就是油
The scum is oil in fact
#给它去掉一点
Let's remove some
#现在盖上锅盖先烧40分钟
Now cover it again and boil it for 40 minutes
#现在我们这个肉已经烧了40分钟了
Now the meat has been boiled for 40 minutes
#我来把这个葱给夹出来
I'm gonna pick out the green onion
#这个 葱都已经烧黄了
It has turned yellow already
#剩下的一些姜也把它夹出来
I'm removing some ginger as well
#因为这个姜和葱放在里面烧太久了之后它就会发酸
If the ginger and the green onion are boiled for too long, they become sour
#影响这个味道
and have a bad effect on the flavor
#好了 现在揭开锅盖来烧
Ok. Now we are boiling it without the lid
#揭开锅盖慢慢烧 烧到它软为止
Boil it slowly until the meat turns soft
#现在有一点软但是还不是特别软
Now it's just a little soft. Not soft enough
#这个颜色也上得差不多了
The color has been absorbed well
#挺不错的
Looks good
#慢慢收汁
Wait for the sauce to be thickened
#不烫啊
Isn't it hot?
#咬的动吗
Can you chew it?
#不够软的话再烧一会儿
We can boil it for a little bit longer if it's not soft enough
#可以了
It's ok
#现在我们大火收汁 收完汁了之后就可以弄起来
Now we are using high heat to thicken the sauce. After that, the dish is ready to serve!
#大家可以看一下这个肉
You can take a look at the meat
#翻炒几下收下汁就可以起锅啦
Stir it again and it's ready!
#好啦 这个肉也差不多啦
Ok! It's almost done!
#把它捞起来
Let's take it out
#把它铲起来
Take it out with the spatula
#一次肯定吃不完
We can't eat it up today
#下次吃的是再加点白菜萝卜进去烧
Next time we can add some cabbage and reddish to boil with the meat
#再加点葱
Some green onion as well
#哦 再加点葱
Yeah. More green onion
#嗯
Hmm
#比较软吧
Soft enough?
#好吃
Yummy!
#所以这个肉比较适合我们老人吃
So this dish is really suitable for old people
#把它炖软一点
Just make the meat softer
#适合老人吃 牙口不好的
Good for elderlies or those without strong teeth
#好吃好吃
Delicious!
#好啦 本期视频就到这里啦
Ok. That's the end of this video
#拜拜
Bye bye!